Finding Aid for Susan Wineberg cookbook collection, 1925-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Susan Wineberg cookbook collection 1925-2004, 1920s-1940s
Wineberg, Susan.
1 linear feet
2010075 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Collection was originally donated by Susan Wineberg (donor no. 5400 ) in 2010.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Susan Wineberg is an Ann Arbor, Michigan local historian.
The Susan Wineberg cookbook collection contains printed recipe books compiled, produced and published by various Michigan manufacturers, food companies, business firms, churches, organizations, and individuals. The collection was originally accumulated from a variety of sources from the donor Susan Weinberg.
The cookbooks are arranged by the name of the town according to geographic location of the compiler, author, or publisher. In cases where items were published by a local division of a large company with multiple locations, the cookbooks are arranged according to the location of such divisions, and not company main headquarters. For example, cookbooks published by the Ann Arbor branch of Michigan Consolidated Gas Company (MCGC) are located with Ann Arbor materials, while publications of the main branch of MCGC can be found with Detroit materials.
The collection contains a handful of items published outside of Michigan, but printed or distributed by Michigan institutions. Such items can be found under Michigan location. For instance Recipe book using G. & I Keses village Halloumi by Cyprus-based G. & I Keses Ltd. is located under its Ann Arbor located distributor, Mediterranean Ventures YNC.
Subjects:
Cookery, American--Michigan.; Recipes--Michigan.; Kitchen appliances.; Food industry and trade--Michigan--Equipment and supplies.; Grocers--Michigan.
- Ann Arbor
  - Ann Arbor Board of Education
    - Try it, you'll like it!! 1972 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Federal Savings
    - Kitchen Kinks. circa 1954 (Box 1)
  - The Ann Arbor News
    - Holiday Cookbook 2002. 2002 (Box 1)
  - Brth Israel Congregation
    - Shall we dance? Recipes for devastatingly delicious desserts. 1999 (Box 1)
  - Democratic Women's Club of the Ann Arbor Area
    - Party primer: 26 menus for elegant entertaining. 1964 (Box 1)
  - Emerson School
    - 1999-2000 Emerson community cookbook: in celebration of Emerson School twenty-fifth anniversary (Box 1)
  - The First Congregational Church
    - Cook book circa 1954 (Box 1)
  - Jewish Community Center Pre-School
    - JCC Pre-school cooks. 1995 (Box 1)
  - League of Catholic Women
    - International recipes, circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - Mediterranean Ventures YNC
    - Recipe book using G. & I. Keses village Halloumi undated (Box 1)
  - Michigan Consolidated Gas Company, Ann Arbor district
    - Christmas greetings 1957 (Box 1)
    - Christmas greetings 1958 (Box 1)
    - Christmas chew-chews, circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - Peters Sausage Company
    - 101 ideas for a quick and easy lunch 1950s (Box 1)
  - Rudolf Steiner School
    - Favorite recipes from Rudolf Steiner School undated (Box 1)
  - Trinity Evangelical Lutheran Church
    - Cookbook circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - Washtenaw Gas Company
    - Recipes. 1934 (Box 1)
  - The White Market
    - The homemaker's meat recipe book. 1948-1949 (Box 1)
    - Meat recipes you'll talk about. 1952 (Box 1)
  - Wilson Dairy
    - The milk calendar 1957 (Box 1)
- Battle Creek
  - A-B Stoves, Inc.
    - The A-B Cook Book 1930s (Box 1)
    - Approved recipes for cookery with gas. 1936 (Box 1)
    - Approved recipes for electric cookery. 1936 (Box 1)
    - Menus with recipes prepared and tested by Modern Priscilla proving plant for A-B gas ranges 1930s (Box 1)
  - Battle Creek Food Company
    - Battle Creek foods and vegetarian recipes 1920s (Box 1)
    - Good eating for health 1920s (Box 1)
    - How to make savory roasts, steaks, croquettes without meat: Protose, a vegetable meat 1920s (Box 1)
    - Modern menus and recipes for your health 1920s (Box 1)
  - Kellogg Company
    - Cereals in candy 1940s (Box 1)
    - Delicious cake recipes 1940s (Box 1)
    - Easy-on-the-budget: main dishes to serve. 1972 (Box 1)
    - Filling the cookie jar, circa 1900s (Box 1)
    - Foreign dishes with American accents circa 1943 (Box 1)
    - Good cooking from Kay Kellogg kitchen 1960s (Box 1)
    - The housewife's year book of health and homemaking. 1937 (Box 1)
    - Kellogg's recipes, circa 1900s (Box 1)
    - The plus food for minus meals 1930s (Box 1)
    - Recipes using Kellogg's corn flakes 1930s (Box 1)
    - Recipes using Kellogg's rice krispies 1930s (Box 1)
    - Refilling the cookie jar, circa 1900s (Box 1)
    - Selected cookie recipes 1940s (Box 1)
    - Supper dishes 1940s (Box 1)
    - Tempting hot breads 1940s (Box 1)
  - Postum Cereal Company, Inc.
    - 101 prize recipes. 1925 (Box 1)
- Bloomfield Hills
  - Cranbrook School
    - Le gala de cuisine. 1997 (Box 1)
- Chelsea
  - Chelsea Milling Company
    - "Jiffy" mixes recipes. 2003 (Box 1)
- Detroit
  - American Motors Corporation
    (see also Kelvinator Leonard, Leonard Refrigerator Co., and Nash-Kelvinator Corporation)
    - From your freezer to you kitchen, to your table: tips on home freezing. 1963 (Box 1)
    - MmmMeals in minutes 1950s (Box 1)
  - Borg-Warner Corporation, Detroit Vapor stove division
    - Star gas range instructions and cook book, circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - Borg-Warner Corporation, Norge Division
    - Cooking with cold. 1939 (Box 1)
    - Cooking with Norge cold. 1941 (Box 1)
    - Electric Cookery with the Norge electric range. 1941 (Box 1)
    - Norge cold cookery and recipe digest. 1947 (Box 1)
  - The Detroit Edison Company
    - Around the world cookery with electric housewares. 1958 (Box 1)
    - Cook better electrically: favor the flavor 1950s (Box 1)
    - Electric cooking: easy as pie 1950s (Box 1)
    - Electric cooking: the easy flameless way. 1966 (Box 1)
    - Patterns for parties, circa 1900s (Box 1)
    - You've come a long way, Lady: employe [sic] wives program. 1972 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Jewel
    - The Detroit Jewel cook book, circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - The Detroit News
    - The art of canning 1950s (Box 1)
    - Pastries and pies, circa 1900s (Box 1)
    - Quick breads, circa 1900s (Box 1)
    - Yeast breads and cakes, circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - Detroit Soda Products Co.
    - Selected recipes demonstrated at Detroit Food & Household Exposition. 1922 (Box 1)
  - Electromaster Inc.
    - Cooking electrically on the Electromaster range 1930s (Box 1)
    - Electric cooking...at its best on the modern Electromaster circa 1938 (Box 1)
    - Electric cooking...at its best on the modern Electromaster 1930s (Box 1)
    - Kitchen tested electric range recipes 1930s (Box 1)
    - Modern cooking with Electrochef. 1930 (Box 1)
    - Recipes circa 1943 (Box 1)
  - Farmer Jack
    - Seafood on the grill 1970s (Box 1)
  - Kelvinator Corporation (Box 1)
    (see Nash-Kelvinator Corporation)
  - Kelvinator Leonard
    (see also American Motors Corporation, Leonard Refrigerator Co., and Nash-Kelvinator Corporation)
    - Your Foodarama: how best to use it and enjoy it 1950s (Box 1)
  - LaChoy Food Products
    - The art and secrets of Chinese cookery, 1931 (Box 1)
    - The art and secrets of Chinese cookery, 1937 (Box 1)
    - LaChoy book of Chinese recipes. 1925 (Box 1)
  - Leonard Refrigerator Co.
    (see also American Motors Corporation, Kelvinator Leonard, and Nash-Kelvinator Corporation.)
    - Delightful dishes from your Leonard 1940s (Box 1)
    - Your Leonard hi-humid refrigerator, circa 1900s (Box 1)
  - Michigan Consolidated Gas Company
    - Christmas greetings 1953 (Box 1)
    - Christmas 1960 (Box 1)
    - Christmas 1961 (Box 1)
    - 1967 (Box 1)
    - Holiday recipes 1972 (Box 1)
  - Nash-Kelvinator Corporation, 2 folders
    (see also American Motors Corporation, Kelvinator Leonard, and Leonard Refrigerator Co.)
    - 23 delicious dishes from 4 frozen "starters" 1950s (Box 1)
    - Better refrigerator recipes by Kelvinator 1930s (Box 1)
    - Cooking with cold. 1933 (Box 1)
    - The miracle of cold 1920s (Box 1)
    - The Kelvinator book of kitchen tested recipes 1930s (Box 1)
    - Your Kelvinator electric range. 1947 (Box 1)
    - Your Kelvinator refrigerator. 1946 (Box 1)
    - Your new Kelvinator electric range. 1950 (Box 1)
    - Yours to enjoy! Your new Kelvinator electric range. 1948 (Box 1)
  - The Peninsular Stove Company
    - And now the new Peninsular automatic electric range: cook book and operating instructions 1930s (Box 1)
  - Universal Cooler Corporation
    - Iced foods. 1926 (Box 1)
  - Wayne County Community College District
    - Celebrating Hispanic heritage cookbook. 2004 (Box 1)
  - WWJ Radio
    - Recipes as heard on "Ask your neighbor" with Bob Allison 1960s (Box 1)
- Dexter
  - Green Acres Shiitake Mushroom Farm
    - All about Shiitake mushrooms: from farm to table 1990s (Box 1)
- East Lansing
  - Michigan State College Extension Division
    - 4-H canning: projects 1-2-3-4-5. 1941 (Box 1)
    - The 4-H club entertains. 1940 (Box 1)
    - Sauces. 1947 (Box 1)
  - Michigan State University Cooperative Extension Service
    - Versatile salads [19--?] (Box 1)
- Frankenmuth
  - Ruth Elizabeth Rupprecht
    - Frankenmuth German-Bavarian cook-book [19--?] (Box 1)
- Hastings
  - Hastings Mutual Insurance Co.
    - Sportsman's kitchen delight. 1970 (Box 1)
- Jackson
  - Loud & Jackson Dairies, Inc.
    - Cottage cheese surprises: 40 recipes for meatless meals, delicious desserts, and 37 salad combinations [19--?] (Box 1)
- Kalamazoo
  - The Kalamazoo Stove & Furnace Company
    - Kalamazoo "Around the World" book. 1951 (Box 1)
- Lansing
  - The Michigan Bean Commission
    - The Michigan bean cookbook circa 1981 (Box 1)
- Oxford
  - Oxford Child Study Club
    - Cookie capers 1940s (Box 1)
- Tecumseh
  - Green Funeral Home
    - Christmas recipes. 1951 (Box 1)
- Other states, unidentified locations, etc.
  - Phil DeGraff
    - Birches, beaches & belches. 1962 (Box 1)
  - Westinghouse Home Economics Institute
    - Your Westinghouse refrigerator: its care and use, over 100 delicious recipes 1940s (Box 1)
  - Unidentified
    - Beth & Michael's special recipes. 1995 (Box 1)